

🗷 frankxu0124@gmail.com 🛭 medium.com/@frankxu0124 📞 9193083187 💡 Durham, NC (willing to relocate) 🛮 in frank-xu-huaze/ 🗘 Frank-Xu-Huaze

SUMMARY

As a Master of Data Science at Duke, I have various experience cleaning and modeling data with Python & R: I ranked top 10% tier in a Kaggle Competition using Convolutional Neural Networks for object detection. I built machine learning pipelines with Google Cloud Platform and brought at least 5% potential profit increase for local companies. I know how to communicate to different audience from my experience working as Data Scientist for companies as big as Wells Fargo, as small as a local start-up, and EPAs. Need sponsorship in the future.

EXPERIENCE

Trade Pending, Data Science Intern, Carrboro, NC

Aug. 2019 - Apr. 2020

Handled the 72-million rows dataset and deployed dashboards used Google Cloud Services, built a Random Forest and provided 92% accuracy on predicting vehicle transaction prices, bringing at least 5% potential profit increase for the product.

Wells Fargo, Data Science Intern, San Francisco, CA

June 2019 - Aug. 2019

 $Analyzed\ customer\ data\ using\ Random\ Forests\ and\ Gradient\ Boosting\ Machines\ to\ recommend\ banking\ products.$

Researched on different methods of interpreting ensemble tree models, bringing more accurate decisions and potential profits for the team.

EPA of Dezhou City, Data Analyst Assistant, Shandong, China

Jan. 2018 - Feb. 2018

Analyzed hourly air pollution with R and presented more than 20 charts every day for the government's project of improving air quality.

EDUCATION

Duke University 2018 - 2020

Master in Interdisciplinary Data Science

Enrolled with an acceptance rate less than 5%

Fudan University 2014 - 2018

Bachelor in Environmental Science

Outstanding Student Scholarship (2015-2017)

Shanghai University of Finance and Economics

2015 - 2017

Minor in Accountancy

PROJECTS

Exploring methods of Feature Interpretation

Feb. 2020 - Mar. 2020

An article exploring new methods of feature interpretation for ensemble tree models available on Python and R.

Kaggle Competition: Identifying Solar PV in Aerial Imagery

Jan. 2019 - Feb. 2019

Used a Convolutional Neural Network built based on MobileNet to achieve a 97.8% accuracy on identifying solar panels in aerial images and ranked 10% tier.

Analyzing Text Data for Real Talk

Sept. 2018 - Feb. 2019

Real Talk is a mobile app available on iOS facing teenager users.

Ran text & regression analysis with R on a dataset of around 1400 stories, unveiled the connection between teenager psychometric status with demographic information.

SKILLS